Mark Anthony Rathbone

Contact Details

HOME ADDRESS

4 Shale Street

Bilston

Wolverhampton

WV14 0HF

PHONE NUMBER

+447984 682775

EMAIL ADDRESS

MarkAnthonyRathbone@gmail.com

WEBSITES

LINKEDIN

GITHUB

MARKRATHBONE.UK



Summary

I am a AWS and Microsoft Certified Cloud Practitioner, in addition I am also a CompTIA A+ Certified IT Technician. In addition I also have 8 years of experience with tech troubleshooting and problem solving.

This year I have attended the AWS re/Start program by Generation. During this course I studied Linux, Shell, Networking, Security, Python and the monitoring, support and application of AWS services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lambda, Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53. After this training course I successfully passed the Certified Cloud Practitioner exam. Since the course finished I have been continuing to study and have studied topics such as Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform and Ansible.

My technical skills also cover mobile devices, networking technology, hardware, virtualization, cloud computer, network troubleshooting, the installation and configuration of Operating Systems, security, software troubleshooting and understanding of operational procedures.

Soft Skills

Communication

Time Management

Teamwork

Growth Mindset

Persistence

Personal Responsibility

Work History

During this programme I studied a 12 week, full-time, classroom based skills development and training on IT fundamentals such as Linux, and learning Python and Shell. In addition I also studied AWS, including the monitoring and support of AWS services and how to apply AWS services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lamda, Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53.

And finally we were also taught some professional skills, improving our verbal and written communication skills, and how to explain technical information and terminology to non-technical end users.

RETAIL STAFF, FAST CAR DIRECT

October 2017 - May 2018

Working with a team of 3 to 5 people each day, my duties involved dealing with customers in person and over the telephone, packaging parcels to specification ready for dispatch, creating advertisement posters in Photoshop, testing technical products for defects and providing technical support to all departments when needed. Having such a large variety of different tasks during my time here showed my versatility in work.

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ASSISTANT, MULTIMEDIA INTERNET CAFÉ

August 2009 - October 2017

My duties involved setting up the store before opening, such as ensuring the shelves were stocked and computers were ready for use by the customers. Once the café had opened, serving customers and assisting and troubleshooting any issues they were having using the computers or any problems with the computers themselves. This could be anything from trying to print a document or an actual hardware fault with the device.

Education & Certifications

CERTIFICATIONS (YOUR ACCLAIM)

2020

AWS re/Start Graduate
Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

2018

CompTIA A+ ce Certification

HEATH PARK BUSINESS & ENTERPRISE COLLEGE

2007 - 2009

GCSE in Mathematics – Grade A

GCSE in English - Grade B

GCSE in Applied Science - Grade B

GCSE in Religious Studies – Grade E

OCR Level 2 National Award in ICT - Pass

BTEC First Certificate in Business Studies - Merit

BTEC First Diploma in Art and Design – Merit